Most AI tutors explain more.
But hearing an answer is not the same as understanding it.
SishyaGuru reverses the conversation: the student teaches, the AI learns, and mastery must be supported by the student's own words.
This is SishyaGuru: “You teach.
AI learns.
You master.”
The left panel is a live concept map, the centre is the teaching conversation, and the right panel shows evidence-backed feedback.
This public demo is clearly labelled Replay, so judges can reproduce it without an API key.
In Live mode, a learner can press Record and teach for up to sixty seconds.
Recording is never continuous.
The learner stops, reviews and edits the transcript, then explicitly submits it.
Nothing auto-submits.
Typing always remains available.
Here I teach how solar energy drives evaporation.
SishyaGuru does not award mastery from fluent prose alone.
GPT-5.6 returns a strict structured assessment, and the application accepts a mastery change only when its evidence quote is an exact substring of my lesson.
The AI learner then asks one focused question.
As I teach condensation, precipitation and collection, the concept map changes with text and icons, not colour alone.
When the explanation contains a misconception, the system cites the exact wording and responds respectfully instead of pretending the concept is secure.
At the end, the summary separates demonstrated strengths from gaps to revisit.
It is formative guidance for this session, not a grade or permanent claim about ability.
The Live path uses GPT-5.6 Structured Outputs with provider storage disabled for assessment requests.
OpenAI transcription creates candidate text, and OpenAI speech renders only the already-validated follow-up question with an AI-generated voice disclosure.
Raw audio and unsubmitted transcript candidates are ephemeral.
Submitted reviewed text stays only in browser-local progress until Clear.
Codex accelerated the architecture, typed contracts, bounded voice adapters, responsive interface and adversarial browser tests.
The release passes thirty-five domain tests, twelve Replay scenarios and seven Live scenarios.
SishyaGuru: master by teaching.